hi there I'm Luis Gomez with palo alto
你好，我是路易斯·戈麦斯和帕洛阿尔托
education and i'd like to share with you
教育，我想和你分享
an awesome application of machine
一个很棒的机器应用程序
learning and neural networks this topic
学习和神经网络这个主题
is called style transfer and what this
被称为风格转移，这是什么
allows us to do is transfer the style of
让我们做的就是转移风格
one image onto another image here you
一个图像到这里你另一个图像
see this really cool gift of an image
看到这个非常酷的图像礼物
changing in real time and as that image
实时变化和图像变化
changes its style is being applied to
改变它的风格正在被应用
the style of the man who's drawing so
那个画画的男人的风格
that's a really cool gift right there
那是一件很酷的礼物
and gives you an idea of what we can do
并让您了解我们可以做些什么
with style transfer technology here are
这里有风格转移技术
the major contributors to this tech
这项技术的主要贡献者
we've got Leon Alexander and Mattias who
我们已经有了莱昂亚历山大和马蒂亚斯谁
all published this paper jointly called
所有发表的这篇论文共同呼吁
a neural algorithm of artistic style
一种艺术风格的神经算法
it's a little bit wordy and if you have
它有点罗嗦，如果你有
a few hours you should definitely -
你 肯定应该几个小时 -
through that because it's a super
通过那， 因为它是一个超级
interesting paper but you got to set
有趣的论文，但你必须设置
aside some time for that one here we've
留出一些时间，一个在这里我们已经
got some pretty applications of style
得到了一些漂亮的风格应用
transfer we've got the Prisma app which
转让我们有Prisma应用程序
started to popularize this a lot more
开始推广这个多很多
and it's really cool as you've real-time
你真实的时候真的很酷
rotate around with your selfie camera
用自拍相机旋转
you've got the style of some piece of
你有一些片的风格
art applied to your video and we've got
艺术应用于您的视频，我们已经
a similar thing going on with that
与此类似的事情
360-degree image to our tap and yeah
360度图像到我们的水龙头和是的
style transfer is just awesome to look
风格转让只是真棒 看
at here I'm not gonna one run through
在这里，我不会经历一次
all these videos there's quite a few
所有这些视频都有不少
videos in this presentation that you
您 在此演示文稿中的视频
should watch on your own because they're
应该自己看，因为他们是
super entertaining but here we've got
超级娱乐，但我们在这里
some oculus VR painting for you and yeah
一些眼睛VR画为你和是啊
it's just pretty to look at man it's
看看男人真是太好了
just just really cool to look at so how
只是真的很酷，看看如何
do we do this how do we accomplish this
我们这样做是如何做到这一点的
well we use something called a
好吧，我们使用的东西叫做a
generative adversarial neural network
生成对抗神经网络
translate about 110 times fast I bet you
翻译约110倍我打赌你
can't okay this this is where it starts
不能这就是它开始的地方
to get confusing so the idea behind it
让它变得混乱所以它背后的想法
the basic idea behind it it's actually
它背后的基本理念实际上就是这样
not that difficult so we've got two
没那么难， 所以我们有两个
neural networks if you've seen any of my
神经网络， 如果你看过我的任何一个
previous videos on neural networks
以前关于神经网络的视频
before then you have an idea of what
在那之前你已经知道了什么
we're gonna do here but if you haven't
我们会在这里做，但如果你没有
that's totally fine too we're gonna
我们也会完全没问题
learn regardless so we've got a
不管学习，我们都有
generator neural network
发电机神经网络
and a discriminator neural network now
现在是一个鉴别器神经网络
an analogy that's used a ton and is
一个类似于使用了吨而且是
super helpful for everyone in the
每个人在超级有用
machine learning community is to think
机器学习社区是思考
of the generator as like a counterfeiter
发电机就像一个伪造者
and to think of the discriminator as
并将鉴别器视为
like a bank official or something like
像银行官员或类似的东西
that whose job it is to prove the
他的工作就是要证明这一点
counterfeiter is making fake images so
伪造者正在伪造图像
yeah these two are pitted against each
是的，这两个人对抗每个人
other and over time the discriminator
其他和随着时间的推移鉴别者
learns more and more to distinguish a
学会越来越多来区分a
fake image and the generator gets better
假图像和发电机变得更好
and better at tricking the discriminator
并且更好地欺骗鉴别者
so what is the generator how does the
什么是发电机怎么样？
generator work well I talked a little
发电机工作得很好我谈了一点
bit about neural networks just now well
关于神经网络的位刚刚好
it generators just a neural network and
它只是一个神经网络和
you feed it just random just garbage
你喂它只是随机只是垃圾
just noise and it will output an image
只是噪音，它会输出一个图像
now this image that it generates is it's
现在它生成的这个图像就是它
counterfeit it is the generated image
伪造它是生成的图像
and let me talk a little bit about what
让我谈谈一下
this latent sample is so if you've never
如果你从来没有，这个潜在的样本是如此
seen this representation of a number
看到了一些这种表示
before that's totally fine it's really
在此之前，它真的非常好
rare to see outside of you know out of
很少见到外面你知道的
machine learning so here is what that
机器学习所以这就是那个
image is trying to show so we've got a
图像试图显示所以我们有一个
number one drawn here and you can see
在这里画的第一，你可以看到
here is like a number and array
这里就像一个数字和数组
representation of this number so all
这个数字的表示如此全部
these zeros correspond to all the white
这些零对应于所有的白色
pixels in this image and these dark gray
此图像中的像素和这些深灰色
and all these values that are above zero
并且所有这些值是大于零
but lower than one these represent the
但低于一个这些代表了
gray and black pixels in this image so
在该图像中灰色和黑色像素，从而
this number eight right here could be
这个数字八在这里可能是
represented in a similar way as that
以类似的方式表示
number one we just saw using a big array
我们刚看到使用大阵列的第一名
of numbers between 0 and 1 so what we do
0到1之间的数字，所以我们做的
is we pass the generator just these
是我们这些刚通过发电机
random noise values and we want it to
随机噪声值，我们希望它
generate some image like that number one
产生这样的头号一些图像
and it does that just by picking values
它只是通过选择值来做到这一点
between 0 and 1 and placing them in the
介于0和1之间并将它们放入
right spots so that's how it would work
正确的位置，这是它的工作方式
with numbers and a similar way would
用数字和类似的方式
work with image
与图像一起工作
so that's the generator the counterfeit
这就是发电机的假冒伪劣
er going back to that analogy and now we
呃回到那个比喻，现在我们
go to the bank official or the
去银行官员或
discriminator the one whose job it is to
鉴别者是其工作的人
tell that those images pass to it are
告诉这些图像传递给它的是
fake or real so the way the
假的还是真的如此
discriminator works well it's just a
鉴别器运作良好它只是一个
basic classifier neural network I say
基本的分类器神经网络我说
basic but it's not that basic but we're
基本的，但它不是那么基本，但我们是
gonna boss over that for now because we
因为我们现在要坚持这个
just want to get the ideas of machine
只是想得到机器的想法
learning right we want those
我们想要那些正确的学习
fundamentals because the lines of code
基础知识， 因为代码行
will change the tools that people will
将改变人们的工具
use will change over time but these
使用会随着时间而 改变 但是这些
ideas ok these are super important ideas
想法确定这些是非常重要的想法
that are helping a lot of people in the
正在帮助很多人在
world right the second so the
世界第一右第二故
discriminator is a basic classifier
鉴别器是一个基本的分类器
neural network model and all it does is
神经网络模型，它所做的就是
just try to tell if an image is real or
试着判断图像是真的还是真的
fake so if you've seen any of my
假的，如果你看过我的任何一个
previous videos we've talked a little
以前的视频我们已经谈了一点
bit about neural networks trying to tell
关于神经网络想要讲述的一点
like a dog and a cow apart trying to
像狗和牛除了努力
identify them when passed an image and
传递图像时识别它们
the way it does that is you pass it a
它的方式是你传递它
bunch of images and they have to be
一堆图像，他们必须
labeled so you're throwing a bunch of
标记为你扔了一堆
images at the neural network and you're
你在神经网络上的图像
labeling them so like throw an image of
标记它们就好像抛出一个图像
dog and make sure it comes with the
狗，并确保它附带
label of dog throw an image of cow make
狗的标签扔牛的图像
sure it comes with the label of cow and
确定它带有牛和牛的标签
you're throwing these labeled images
你扔这些标记的图像
into the neural network feeding it over
进入神经网络喂它
and over and over again and over time it
它一遍又一遍地
learns to extract features like curves
学会提取曲线等特征
and lines and like distances between
和线之间的距离
eyes and lengths of face and things like
眼睛和长度的脸和类似的东西
that and over time it gets really smart
随着时间的推移，它变得非常聪明
and it learns what in images now instead
它现在可以学习图像中的内容
of having two classes or instead of
的具有两个类或代替
having classes like animals like dogs
像狗一样的动物课
and cats and cows like we might have
和 我们可能拥有的 猫和奶牛一样
seen before with neural networks we're
我们之前看过神经网络
only gonna have two classes okay this is
只是要具备两个班没关系，这是
also called a binary classifier because
也称为二元分类器因为
we've only got two options here and the
我们只有两个选择这里和
two options are real and fake so
两个选项是真实的和假的
obviously it wants to be able to tell
显然它希望能够分辨出来
that the generated images are fake and
生成的图像是假的
that the training data that we pass it
我们传递的训练数据
are real so let's put this all together
是真的所以让我们把这一切都放在一起
with this really nice imagery right here
这个非常好的图像就在这里
so we've got our pull that pointer up
所以我们把指针拉了起来
we've got our latent sample right here
我们的潜在样本就在这里
just random noise being fed into the
只是随机噪声被送入
generator the generator does some neural
发电机发电机做了一些神经
network stuff on it and spits out a new
网络上的东西， 并吐出一个新的
image this is a really stupid neural
这是一个非常愚蠢的神经
network okay it's really dumb right now
网络好吧，现在真的很蠢
because it hasn't had a lot of training
因为它没有经过很多培训
to go off and this discriminator right
离开这个鉴别器吧
now is also pretty dumb this is the
现在这也是相当愚蠢的
beginning stages so it might not even be
开始阶段，因此甚至可能不
able to tell the difference between this
能告诉 这之间的区别
and this image so as this generator is
这个图像就像这个发生器一样
generating images and passing it into
生成图像并将其传递给
the discriminator we got training data
鉴别器我们得到了训练数据
over here and we're pooling samples out
在这里，我们正在汇集样品
of it and also passing that to the
它还传递给了
discriminator so over time it's getting
鉴别者所以随着时间的推移它会越来越多
trained on real data fake data it's
它训练有关真实数据的假数据
getting real data and then fake data and
获取真实数据然后伪造数据和
it's trying to distinguish which one is
它试图区分哪个是
real which one is fake and over time it
真实哪一个是假的，随着时间的推移呢
learns the difference and as the
了解差异并作为
discriminator gets smarter the generator
鉴别器使发电机更智能
starts making better and better images
开始制作更好更好的图像
which are more likely to fool a
哪个更容易愚弄
discriminator here's a cool little video
鉴别家这里是一个很酷的小视频
of the discriminator and generator being
鉴别器和发生器的存在
trained and you can see that their
训练有素， 你可以看到他们的
curves are getting super close generated
曲线越来越紧密
data is starting to get super close to
数据开始越来越接近
that real data right there and as it
真正的数据在那里，当它
gets closer and closer that
越来越近了
discriminator is going to get fooled
鉴别者会被愚弄
more often which means the generator is
更常见的是发电机
going to be putting out better and
将会更好地推出
better more real looking images so
更好看的真实图像
here's an example of style transfer
这是风格转移的一个例子
being used
正在使用
we've got just random noise right here
我们这里只有随机噪音
and we're applying the style of this
我们正在应用这种风格
beautiful classic van Gogh starry night
美丽的经典梵高繁星之夜
and here's an example of what the image
这是图像的一个例子
might look like after one layer of the
看起来像的一层后，
neural network of the generator neural
发电机神经网络的神经网络
network here's an example of the next
网络这里是下一个的例子
layer the next layer and at this final
层中的下一层，并在该最终
layer you can see it's starting to
你可以看到它开始的层
really have the similar have a similar
真的有类似的有类似的
vibe to this starry night image and on
感受这个繁星满天的夜晚形象
the bottom here we get a similar type of
这里的底部我们得到了一个相似类型的
thing where instead of a picture of
事情在那里 的照片，而不是
sorry night we've got this picture of a
对不起晚上，我们已经有了 的 这张照片
house and we start to see it get
房子，我们开始看到它
as the style is transferred on to that
因为风格转移到那个
image so here's some must-reads in
这是一些必读的图片
computer vision so computer vision is
计算机视觉所以计算机视觉是
the topic of all kinds of all kinds of
各种各类的话题
machine learning tasks and trying to get
机器学习任务并试图获得
computers to play around with images so
电脑玩弄图像所以
yeah these are some good books on the
是的， 这些都是一些好书
topic and will help you understand much
主题，将帮助您了解更多
more of the context behind generative
生成背后​​的背景更多
additive behind generative adversarial
生成对抗背后的附加物
neural networks here's a really cool
这里的神经网络非常酷
really entertaining video on AI and art
人工智能和艺术的真实娱乐视频
I approve of the music I'll let you
我赞成我会告诉你的音乐
watch that on your own time super
在你自己的时间观看超级
entertaining really short - it's only
娱乐真的很短 - 这是唯一的
like five minute video and here is more
像五分钟的视频，这里更多
of a keynote type of speech about this
关于这一点的主题演讲
the style transfer technology so if
风格转移技术如果
you're super interested in you want to
你对你想要的超级感兴趣
dive even deeper into this I would
更深潜入这个我会
highly recommend watching this talk and
强烈推荐观看此演讲
finally here's some more applications of
最后这里是一些更多的应用程序
style transfer it's not just used to
风格转移它不仅仅是习惯
transfer like famous paintings on to
像着名画作一样转移到
some regular image it can also be used
一些常规图像也可以使用
to enhance regular old photography so
这样可以增强经常的老摄影
here we've got this sunken Solon field
在这里，我们有了沉没的Solon领域
right here and here we've got this
就在这里，我们已经有了这个
beautiful rich vibrant field with a nice
美丽富饶的充满活力的田野，很棒
big red log cabin in the middle and by
大红色小木屋在中间和
using style transfer we can brighten up
使用风格转移，我们可以照亮
this image make that grass look more
这个图像使草看起来更多
lively and give that sky a really nice
活泼，让天空变得非常好
deep blue color and we can also do
深蓝色我们也可以做
something like this where we have a
像这样的东西，我们有一个
light image and we apply to it a
光图像，我们应用到它
beautiful sunset landscape with deep
美丽的日落景观与深
reds and deep purples and apply that
红色和深紫色并应用它
style to the image to make it look like
风格到图像，使它看起来像
it was taken at night in this
这是在晚上拍摄的
otherworldly magical location yeah I
超凡脱俗的神奇地点，是的，我
thought this was pretty funny style
以为这是非常有趣的风格
transfer can also be used to transform
转移也可以用来改造
furniture designs maybe IKEA is already
家具设计也许宜家已经是
on the neural network hype I don't know
关于神经网络炒作我不知道
so those are a lot of really cool
所以这些都是很多很酷的
applications of style transfer and I
风格转移的应用和我
think it'd be really great if we
认为，如果我们这将会是真正伟大的
make our own right now if we could train
如果我们能够训练，现在就自己做
our own style transfer neural networks
我们自己的风格转移神经网络
so we're gonna use this thing called
所以我们要用这个叫做的东西
disco Gann now this is a pretty recent
迪斯科江恩现在这是一个非常新近
one so it should give us some really
一个真的应该给我们一些
cool looking results and here's a
很酷的结果，这里是一个
flowchart of the basic process we're
我们基本流程的流程图
going to go through so I'll let you look
要经过，所以我就让你看看
over that and start thinking about how
在那之后，开始考虑如何
we're gonna do this and I'm gonna pull
我们要这样做，我要拉
my environment up and we're gonna run
我的环境，我们会跑
through some code live
通过一些代码直播
you
您
all right so let's get into this live
好的，让我们进入现场直播
coding to do some style transfer using
使用编码进行一些样式传输
neural networks so we're not gonna do
神经网络，所以我们不会这样做
Ganz today just because the code is
Ganz今天只是因为代码是
super crazy to look at and to think
超级疯狂地看待和思考
about so instead of training two neural
关于这样而不是训练两个神经
networks to fight against each other
网络自相残杀
like we talked about earlier what we're
就像我们前面谈到的就是我们
gonna do is we're gonna use one neural
要做的是我们要使用一个神经元
network to mix together two images this
网络将这两个图像混合在一起
is gonna be great for you guys and
对你们来说 会很棒
you'll be able to still see some real
你将能够看到一些真实的东西
examples of styles transfer happening
风格的例子发生转移
right under your fingertips as we run
在我们跑步的时候，在你的指尖
this code holding shift and hitting
此代码保持移位和击中
enter allow you to run a cell here so
输入允许你在这里运行一个单元格
just make sure you hit shift enter and
只要确保你打移位进入和
that'll take you through each cell so
这将带你通过每个细胞
let's start off with cell one right here
让我们先从小区的一个就在这里
and we run this and we see it shows us
我们运行这个，我们看到它向我们展示
this nice big image of content style and
内容风格这个漂亮的大图像和
mixed images so this is a super helpful
混合图像所以这是一个超级有用的
graphic to refer to and gives you a
图形引用并给你一个
really good idea of what we're gonna be
什么 ，我们会 做得很好的主意
doing today so we've got our content
今天做，所以我们得到了我们的内容
image and our style image and these are
图像和我们的风格图像，这些都是
both being fed into the neural network
两者都被送入神经网络
so the neural network is going to be
所以神经网络将成为现实
extracting lines and curves from our
从我们的提取线和曲线
content image and it's going to be
内容图片，它将会是
extracting textures and colors from our
从我们的提取纹理和颜色
style image and it's going to be running
风格图像，它将运行
these through neural network extracting
这些通过神经网络提取
features and it's going to be adding the
功能，它将添加
the features that it extracts it's going
它提取它会 功能
to do something called calculate a
做一个叫做计算的东西
gradient and it's going to use these
渐变，它将使用这些
gradients that it finds to update this
它发现更新的渐变
blank image which will slowly over time
空白图像会慢慢地随着时间推移
turn into a mixed image containing the
变成一个包含的混合图像
lines from this content image and the
来自此内容图片的行和
textures and colors from the style image
风格图像中的纹理和颜色
so here we've got our imports very
所以我们这里的进口很多
important so we've got to import this
重要的是我们必须导入这个
right here matplotlib inline this just
就在这里matplotlib内联这个只是
allows us to display images like this
允许我们显示这样的图像
one in this notebook instead of popping
一个在这个笔记本而不是弹出
out a separate window so that's all that
出了一个单独的窗口就是这样
does import matplotlib this is allows us
导入matplotlib这是允许我们
to do graphing and displaying images
做图形和显示图像
like I said within this notebook that
就像我在这个笔记本中说的那样
we're in here tensorflow is a library by
我们在这里tensorflow是一个库
Google which allows us to do a lot of
谷歌允许我们做了很多的
common neural network tasks super easily
常见的神经网络任务非常容易
so that's gonna save us a lot of work
所以这会为我们节省了大量的工作
numpy allows us to do matrix math
numpy允许我们做矩阵数学
and that's just complex number
这只是一个复杂的数字
operations with we have like squares and
我们的操作有广场和
blocks of numbers instead of just like
数字块而不是像
one number times one number so this
一个数字乘以一个数字所以这个
allows us to do those matrix matrix
允许我们做那些矩阵矩阵
operations and pillow which we import as
我们导入的操作和枕头
pill that image is just a library which
药丸，图像只是一个库，
allows us to do common image tasks in
允许我们在中进行常见的图像任务
Python and vgg 16 which is our final
Python和vgg16这是我们的决赛
import here is something that the author
这里导入的是作者的东西
has created for us and it is a wrapper
为我们创造了它，它是一个包装
oops
哎呀
it is a wrapper not like M&M it is a
它是包装不喜欢M＆M 这是一个
it's a it's a simplification that allows
这是一个允许的简化
us to create this bgg 16 neural network
我们来创建这个bgg16神经网络
super easily and what this is is just
超级容易，这是什么
like a it's just a type of neural
就像它只是一种神经
network and is used commonly when
网络和常用的时候
working with images so the author curry
使用图像，所以作者咖喱
of this of these files created us a nice
这些文件中的这些创建了我们一个很好的
vgg 16 module that we import here that
我们在这里导入的vgg 16模块
allows us to create a big neural network
允许我们创建一个大的神经网络
used for working on images super easily
用于超级轻松地处理图像
so that's what vgg 16 does so now we're
这就是 现在我们 所做的vgg 16所做的事情
going to get into like the appetizer
要像 开胃菜 一样进入
code alright this is gonna be all the
码好起来的，这是要去的所有
helper functions that are gonna let us
帮助函数，它们将让我们
feed our neural network in a super
以超级的方式喂养我们的神经网络
consistent way
一致的方式
so load image uses our our image library
所以加载图像使用我们的图像库
our pillow this pill image library that
我们的枕头这个药丸图像库
I talked about and what it's gonna do is
我谈到了它将要做的事情
load images in a very specific way it's
它以非常特定的方式加载图像
going to load an image it's going to
要加载它将要加载的图像
resize it to the proper size and shape
将其调整到适当的大小和形状
and it's going to allow us to have all
而这将让我们拥有所有
of these images in the same exact format
这些图像的格式相同
this is super important when working
这在工作时非常重要
with neural networks any data you feed
使用神经网络您输入的任何数据
into it you typically want it to all be
进入它你通常想要它
the same type of format so same shape
相同类型的格式如此相同的形状
same file extension
同一文件扩展名
all that good stuff so that's what load
所有那些好东西，这就是负载
image does save image gets us the file
图像保存图像获取文件
extension of JPEG and makes sure that
JPEG的扩展，并确保
all the images have the same color
所有图像都具有相同的颜色
values all the same range of color
值相同的颜色范围
values so that we've got the same exact
价值使我们得到了同样的精确度
type of images being fed into the neural
被送入神经的图像类型
network plot image big just allows us to
网络情节图片大只允许我们
plot a big image inside of this notebook
绘制这款笔记本 内部的大图
and this is what we're going to use to
这就是我们要用的东西
display our final mixed image with the
显示我们的最终混合图像
style transfer
风格转移
to it plot images this is just to
对它绘制图像这只是为了
display images nicely at the very end so
显示图像很好地在最端部，以便
now we get into the meat of the neural
现在我们进入了神经的肉体
network code here so loss functions are
网络代码在这里所以损失函数是
a super important topic to learn about
一个值得学习的超级重要主题
and we're not going to go into all the
而我们不会进入所有的
math but I'm going to give you a good
数学，但我会给你一个好的
idea of what loss functions are and why
了解损失功能是什么以及为什么
they're used so we give our computer a
他们被使用，所以我们给我们的电脑一个
general direction and using a loss
总体方向和使用损失
function machine learning algorithms are
功能机器学习算法是
able to to get closer and closer and
能够得到密切和
closer to that goal over time so the
随着时间的推移接近那个目标所以
loss function we're gonna be using here
我们将在这里使用的损失函数
is mean squared error alright so let's
是平均误差好，所以让我们
get into the real meat of all this
深入了解这一切
neural network style transfer code so
神经网络样式转移代码
this create content loss function is
这个创建内容丢失功能
pretty important so we're gonna walk
非常重要，所以我们要走路了
through it pretty much line by line so
通过它几乎一行一行
you already know by the name of the
你已经通过的名字知道
function that it's going to have
功能这将有
something to do with a loss function
与损失函数有关
which is used to optimize in neural
用于优化神经系统
networks and it's also going to have to
网络，它也将不得不
do with our content image specifically
我们专门针对我们的内容图片
and the content image remember is the
并且记住的内容图像是
image that we're gonna get the curves
我们要得到曲线的图像
and lines from in our final style
和我们最终风格的线条
transferred image just by the name of
转移图像只是名称
this function we already know a lot
这个功能我们已经了解了很多
about what it's going to do but let's
关于它将要做什么，但让我们做
dive deeper into the code and see
深入探讨代码，看看
exactly what's happening here so this
到底发生了什么，所以这个
feed dict line what this is doing is
喂dict line这是做什么的
it's telling the neural network very
它非常地告诉神经网络
explicitly hey we're going to feed you
显然， 嘿，我们要喂你
an image and the image we're going to
一个图像和我们要去的图像
feed you is this content image right
喂你就是这个内容形象吧
here and if you're wondering where that
在这里，如果你想知道在哪里
content image is coming through well
内容图片很顺利
it's right up here it's going to get
它就在这里它会得到
passed into this function as we call it
我们称之为传递给这个函数
so layers this line right here is going
所以层这条线在这里是怎么回事
to get the the layers that the fed image
得到的层，所述馈图像
is moving through in the neural network
正在通过神经网络
so here we tell the model hey this is
所以在这里我们告诉模型嘿这是
the image we want to feed to you and
我们想要给你的形象
this line is saying hey give me all the
这条线说嘿，给我所有的
layers that this image is going to move
层， 该图像将移动
through now we're going to calculate the
到现在为止我们要计算一下
actual values that the image now we're
现在我们的图像的实际值
going to calculate the actual values
要计算实际值
that the neural network calculates when
神经网络计算何时
we move the image through the layers of
我们通过层层移动图像
the neural network which we received
我们收到的神经网络
here so the way we do that is using this
在这里，我们这样做的方式就是使用它
super nice tensor flow
超级好的张量流
function just called session run and all
函数刚刚调用会话运行和所有
we do is we give it layers and we give
我们做的是我们给它层，我们给
it an image the results of running that
它是运行结果的图像
image through all those layers that
通过所有这些层图像即
needs to go through will be now stored
需要通过将现在存储
in the values variable so what this is
在值变量中，这是什么
doing is just making a big placeholder
做就是做一个大占位符
for all the losses we're about to be
因为我们即将面临的所有损失
computing and this for loop right here
计算和这个for循环就在这里
so remember value is all the values
所以记住价值就是所有的价值观
after the image has been passed through
图像通过后
all the layers and layer is all of the
所有的层和层都是
layers of the neural network that the
那层神经网络
image is going to be passed through so
图像是要通过这样传递
we're going to move through all of these
我们正在经历所有 这些 移动
values and layers and we're going to
价值观和层次，我们要去
apply a loss function to each layer and
对每一层都 应用一个损失函数
each value so we apply that loss
每个值， 所以我们应用该损失
function store it in this lost variable
函数将它存储在这个丢失的变量中
and then we toss that into our big
然后我们把它扔进我们的大
placeholder layer losses so this is
占位符层损失所以这是
actually not going to hold any values
实际上不会持有任何价值观
for now this is just going to hold loss
现在这只是亏本
functions so we're gonna store the
功能所以我们要存储
functions that we want to run later in
我们要在以后运行功能
this array and total loss once we've
一旦我们这个阵列和全部损失
stored all of those loss functions in
存储了所有这些损失函数
the array and we exit this loop we're
数组， 我们退出这个循环
gonna hop back out of there and we're
要跳出那里，我们就是
going to just take the average of all
要只取 所有的平均值
those loss functions and what they
那些损失的功能和它们是什么
computed and we're going to return this
计算，我们将返回此
total loss high level idea of what this
总亏损高水平的想法是什么
function is doing is it's feeding the
功能做的是它的喂养
neural network our content image which
神经网络我们的内容图像
we want to find lines and shapes of it's
我们想找到线条和形状的这
feeding our neural network that image
为我们的神经网络提供图像
through some very specific layers and
通过一些非常具体的层和
then it's using something called a loss
那么它正在使用一种称为损失的东西
function to calculate an optimization I
函数计算优化I
don't know how you're going to extract
不知道你将如何提取
features but use this loss function and
功能，但使用此损失功能和
that's your direction all right so now
这就是你现在的方向
we're gonna do something similar with
我们该怎么做类似的事情
the style image so what we're gonna do
风格的形象， 所以我们要做的
is use this thing called a gram matrix
使用这个称为克矩阵的东西
and we don't need to know exactly what a
我们不需要确切地知道什么是
grande matrix is because that's a big
格兰德矩阵是因为这是一个很大的
linear algebra thing so we're just gonna
线性代数的事情， 所以我们要去
keep in mind that this whole purpose of
请记住这个目的
the gram matrix is to figure out which
克矩阵是要弄清楚哪个
features in the style layers of the
样式层中的特征
neural network will activate when we
神经网络将在我们激活时激活
pass it in the style image and then when
将它传递给样式图像然后何时传递
we find out what parts of the style
我们找出了风格的哪些部分
layers in the neural net
神经网络中的层
are activating when we pass it the style
当我们传递它的风格时激活
image we're going to copy this into our
我们要把它复制到我们的图片中
mixed image and what that does is
混合图像和它的作用
basically extract all the colors and
基本上提取所有的颜色和
textures from our style image paste that
我们的样式图像粘贴的纹理
into the mixed image so just like up
进入混合图像就好了
here with the content loss where we're
这里的内容丢失我们在哪里
extracting all the contours all the
全部提取所有轮廓
lines all the shapes out of our content
排列我们内容的所有形状
image and pasting that into the mixed
图像和粘贴到混合
image here is where this Graham matrix
这里的图像就是这个格雷厄姆矩阵
function and this create style loss is
功能和这创造风格损失是
what's going to allow us to copy and
什么会让我们复制和
paste the colors and textures from our
粘贴颜色和纹理我们
style image into the mixed image all
风格图像全部融入混合图像
right so this create denoise loss this
这样就可以减少这种损失
is yet another loss function but we're
是另一个损失函数，但我们是
not going to talk about this one because
不打算谈论这个，因为一个
it's not as important as the other two
它没有其他两个那么重要
all that this one does is make the image
所有这一切都是制作图像
a little bit clearer so we're not going
更清楚一点， 所以我们不去
to talk about that for now but make sure
现在 谈谈这个， 但要确保
to run it again with shift-enter and
用shift-enter再次运行它
here is where we actually do the style
这里是我们实际风格的地方
transferring this is what's going to run
转移这是将要运行的
both of those loss functions that we
这两方面的损失函数，我们
created earlier and actually combine
早期创建并实际组合
them and paste them into our mixed image
将它们粘贴到我们的混合图像中
so we're going to use something called
所以我们要用一些叫做的东西
gradient descent now gradient descent is
梯度下降现在梯度下降了
a way of finding the local minimum and
寻找当地最低点和最低点的方法
we want to find the local minimum
我们想找到当地的最低要求
because we want our loss to be as small
因为我们希望我们的损失一样小
as possible because when our loss is as
作为可能的，因为当我们的损失是
small as possible our mixed image will
我们的混合图像会尽可能小
have the most of the contours that it
拥有它的大部分轮廓
can get from our content image and the
可以从我们的内容图像和
most possible amount of colors and
最可能的颜色和
textures as it can have from our style
它可以从我们的风格中获得纹理
image so our goal right here is to
图像所以我们的目标就在这里
minimize both of those loss functions
最小化这两种损失函数
that we created earlier and the way we
我们之前创建的以及我们的方式
do that is this technique called
这就是这种技术
gradient descent so the idea behind
渐渐下降所以背后的想法
gradient descent is like if you think of
梯度下降就像你想到的那样
of like a ball rolling down a hill the
就像一个滚下山坡的球
way that a ball rolls down a hill it
球滚下山的方式
doesn't go from like here all the way to
不是像这里一直走到的
the bottom of the hill right a ball
山脚下右边一个球
incrementally rolls down the hill and if
逐渐滚下山坡，如果
there are like some curves in the
有一些曲线
hillside the ball might have to take a
球在山坡上可能需要拿一个
bit of a winding path to get to the
蜿蜒的小路位才能到
bottom gradient descent is the same idea
底部梯度下降是同一个想法
so except instead of walking down
所以除了不要走路
Hill we're walking down a like 50
希尔我们走了50级
dimensional who knows how many
维谁知道多少
dimensions to get to the bottom of that
要达到底部的尺寸
loss function space
损失函数空间
so yeah that's what gradient descent so
所以是的，这就是梯度下降所以
we're gonna use gradient descent to get
我们将使用渐变下降来获得
our loss as small as possible to make
我们尽可能小的损失，使
sure we can pull as many features as
我们确定可以提取尽可能多的功能
possible out of our content image and
我们的内容图片和
our style image to combine them into our
我们的风格形象将它们融入我们的
mixed image so yeah that's the big idea
混合图像所以是的，这是个大主意
with this style transfer function and
具有这种风格转移功能和
here you see we're doing our nice tensor
在这里，你看到我们正在做着很好的张量
flow stuff we're going to get the layers
流动的东西，我们将得到层
of the neural network we want to use
我们想要使用的神经网络
which is our we're getting different
这是我们的不同之处
layers out of the neural network we want
层出我们想要 的神经网络
to use here and here and these are
在这里和这里使用这些都是
content layers and our style layers so
内容层和我们的风格层，从而
we're going to be using different layers
我们将使用不同的图层
for the content image and the style
对于内容图像和样式
image and here we make that loss
图像，在这里我们做了那个损失
function using those those methods that
功能使用那些方法
we defined above
我们在上面定义
so we've got loss for our content image
所以我们的内容图片已经丢失了
loss for our style image and again loss
失去我们的风格形象，再次失去
for the D noise but we don't want to
对于D噪声，但我们不想
focus on this right now all this does is
关注这个，现在所有这样做是
help the image be a little bit less
帮助图像少一点
noisy so yeah now we're getting the
吵，所以是的， 现在我们得到了
actual variables and in tensor flow what
实际变量和张量流量是什么
a variable is is some value that we want
变量是我们想要的一些值
to change so telling tensorflow that
改变这样告诉tensorflow那
you're making a new variable is telling
你正在制作一个新的变量
it hey make sure after every iteration
嘿 每次迭代后确认
of running those loss functions make
运行那些损失函数
sure you update the variables so the
确定你更新变量所以
variables we want to update are the
我们想要更新的变量是
content variables and the style
内容变量和样式
variables because over time we want to
变量， 因为我们想要 随着时间的推移
be able to pull more and more
能够拉越来越多
information out of these images and we
这些图像和我们的信息
also make a variable for the D noise
也为D噪音制作变量
just like we did earlier but we're gonna
就像我们之前做的那样，但我们会的
continue glossing over this because
继续掩盖这一点， 因为
remember anytime you see D noise in this
记得任何时候你看到D噪音
file all it's doing is helping to make
文件所做的一切正在帮助制作
the image a little bit clearer and less
图像更清晰，更少
noisy so now we're going to make a new
吵，所以现在我们要做一个新的
tensorflow session using this session
使用此会话的tensorflow会话
run call and all that does is allows
运行调用，所有这一切都是允许的
tensorflow to build this big graph of
tensorflow构建这个大图
all the mathematical stuff that it needs
它需要的所有数学东西
to do and we get to do that just one
要做，我们只做一个
line using session dot run and passing
使用会话点运行和传递的行
it the things that we wanted to do
它是我们想要做的事情
computations on so that's really cool
计算， 这真的很酷
tensor flow is a real game changer when
张量流是一个真正的游戏改变者
it came out so here is where we actually
它出来了，所以这里是我们实际的地方
tell tensor flow how to update those so
告诉张量流如何更新那些
here is where we're writing the code
这是我们编写代码的地方
that tells tensor flow how much to
这告诉张量流量到底有多少
update our variables by and make sure
通过更新我们的变量并确保
that it's just the tiniest incremental
它只是最微小的增量
improvement because we want to descend
改善， 因为我们想要下降
slowly okay the big thing with using
慢慢好 使用的一件大事
gradient descent is if you imagine that
梯度下降就是你想象的那样
if you imagine that ball rolling down a
如果你想象那个球滚下来了
hill example a ball can roll down a hill
山例如一个球可以滚下山
and then roll back and forth right we
然后我们来回滚动吧
don't want that so we want our ball to
不要那样我们想要我们的球
move a little slower we want it to move
移动速度慢一点，我们希望它移动
we want it to move down in tiny little
我们希望它在微小的一点点向下移动
steps so that it doesn't overshoot and
步骤， 以便它不会超调和
come up the start coming up the other
从另一个开始出现
side of the hill here's where we combine
这边的山坡是我们结合的地方
the loss here is the part where we're
这里的损失是我们所在的部分
going to actually combine those losses
实际上将这些损失结合起来
get that gradient that we calculated up
得到我们计算出的渐变
here getting all of those tensors
在这里得到所有这些张量
getting all those big big squares of
得到所有那些大的广场
numbers that we want to start updating
我们想要开始更新的数字
and store them in this run list variable
并将它们存储在此运行列表变量中
and mixed image here's where we
和混合图像在这里我们
initialize our mixed image so all we're
初始化我们的混合图像所以我们都是
gonna do with this is make a new big
这将是一个新的大事
block of pixels which will represent a
将代表a的像素块
new image and just fill it with random
新图像，只需随机填写
noise that's all that the mix image is
噪音就是混合图像的全部
going to start out as and now we feed
从头开始，现在我们喂
our mixed image into the neural network
我们的混合图像进入神经网络
so that it can start getting all those
这样它就可以开始获得所有这些
features out of our content and style
我们的内容和风格
image and yeah and that that's pretty
图像，是的，那很漂亮
much what the rest of this code does is
这个代码的其余部分是做什么的
it feeds the mixed image into the neural
它将混合图像输入神经元
network at the same time as the content
网络同时作为内容
and style imagers are going in to
和风格成像仪进入
extract their features and the mixed
提取他们的特征和混合
image is going in right along with them
图像与他们的权利以及 在去
so that it can get applied all of the
这样它就可以应用所有的
features that the neural network is
神经网络的特征
extracting on our other two images and
提取我们的其他两个图像和
yeah that's it that's all the neural
是的，这就是所有的神经
network code alright cool so let's run
网络代码好吧，所以让我们运行
this
这个
shift-enter so it's okay if you didn't
shift-enter 所以如果你没有，那也没关系
understand most or any of that really
了解大多数或任何真正的
what I want you to get out of that is
我想让你摆脱的是
the high-level idea of being able to
能够的高层次想法
feed images into a neural network trying
将图像输入神经网络尝试
to think about loss functions and
考虑损失函数和
gradient descent and just so you can see
梯度下降，你可以看到
some of the real-life code that we use
我们使用的一些现实代码
in machine learning and the real actual
在机器学习和真实的实际
tools that we use so and yeah I just
我们使用的工具，是的，我只是
want you to expose you to those concepts
希望您向您展示这些概念
and show you how we use them in real
并告诉你我们如何在真实中使用它们
life code so don't worry if you didn't
生活密码所以不要担心，如果你没有
understand most of that it's totally
完全理解它的大部分内容
fine it'll take you a while to
很好， 它会花费你一段时间
understand all this stuff it took me it
了解它带给我的所有这些东西
took me along a long time and I'm still
带我走了很长一段时间，我还在
learning new stuff about this every day
每天都在学习新的东西
pretty much so here's an example of how
几乎所以这里有一个如何的例子
to take all that code that we just wrote
把所有的代码，我们只是写
and how to actually run our images right
以及如何正确运行我们的图像
because we never specified like hey take
因为我们从来没有像嘿那样指定
this style image and take this content
这个风格的形象，并采取这个内容
image
图片
well this code is going to show you how
那么这段代码将告诉你如何
to actually feed the images that you
实际上喂你的图像
want into that neural network and do all
想要进入那个神经网络并做所有事情
of that style transferring stuff so
这种风格转移的东西
here's an example we're gonna load this
这是一个例子， 我们要加载它
willy wonka old image and that's just
威利wonka老图像，这是公正的
stored in this images folder and it's
存储在此图像文件夹中，它是
called
叫
willy wonka old so you can see it's just
willy wonka old所以你可以看到它只是
getting going into that images directory
进入该图像目录
and getting that oops images directory
并得到那个oops图像目录
and getting that willy wonka old that
并得到了那个willy wonka那个
jpg image using that load image function
使用该加载图像功能的 jpg图像
we talked about way back up here to just
我们谈论的方式回到了这里只是
load that image in a very specific way
以非常特定的方式加载该图像
and we do the same thing for our style
我们为自己的风格做同样的事情
image and this is located in the same
图像和它位于相同的位置
folder right here and it's just called
文件夹就在这里，它刚刚被调用
style 7 so let's hit shift enter to load
样式7所以让我们点击shift进入加载
these we're going to use only the fourth
这些我们只会使用第四个
layer of our vgg 16 neural network to
我们的vgg 16神经网络层
get the contours and the lines out of
得到的轮廓和线条出来
our content image this is just like an
我们的内容图片就像一个
experimentation thing the author just
作者只做实验
tried a bunch of different layers to see
尝试了一堆不同的层来看
which one was getting the best lines out
其中之一是得到最好的线条勾勒出
of the content image and it just turned
内容画面的，它刚满
out that 4 was the best layer of the
指出，4是的最佳层
neural network to extract lines and
神经网络提取线和
contours so we're using that fourth
轮廓所以我们正在使用第四个
layer and now we're getting all of
层，现在我们得到了所有
the layers the bgg 16 model has 13
的BGG 16模型具有13层
layers and here we're just getting all
层，在这里， 我们只是得到了所有
13 of those layers to run our style
这些图层中有 13 个是我们的风格
image through and now we've run our
图像通过，现在我们运行我们的
style transfer function and train our
风格转移功能和训练我们的
neural network to transfer the style of
神经网络转移的风格
one image and to combine the textures
一个图像和组合纹理
and colors from one image and the lines
和一个图像和线条的颜色
and shapes from another image into a
从另一个图像到另一个图像的形状
mixed image to create our final style
混合图像来创造我们的最终风格
transfer result and yeah just run that
转移结果，是的，只是运行
and thankfully I have a pretty fast
谢天谢地，我的速度很快
computer so I'll just show you the
电脑，所以我只会告诉你
training right here and yeah we'll see
在这里训练，是的，我们会看到
how all these images are printed out and
如何将所有这些图像打印出来，
yeah we'll just watch this train for a
是啊，我们就只是看这列火车的
few minutes
一会儿
all right neural networks done training
好的神经网络完成了训练
and we've got our mixed image only took
我们的混合图像只是拍摄的
me cool final image wow that looks
我很酷的最终形象哇看起来
really gross
真的很糟糕
took me three minutes and 52 seconds to
花了我3分52秒
get to this final image here there you
得到这个最终的形象在这里有你
go there's there is chlorophyll infested
去那里有叶绿素出没
willy wonka so he took the lines and
willy wonka所以他采取了行和
contours of this image pasted them into
这张图片的轮廓将它们粘贴进去
here the colors and textures of this
这里的颜色和纹理这
image pasted them into here and we got
图像粘贴到这里，我们得到了
this really gross looking willy wonka
这真是看起来很威利威尔卡
mixed image using style transfer with a
使用样式传输的混合图像
neural network from lines so I want to
从线的神经网络，所以我想
hammer these ideas into your head of
把这些想法锤入你的脑袋
gradient descent loss functions and I
梯度下降损失函数和我
want you to read about them on your own
要你了解他们对自己的
because they're super interesting and
因为他们非常有趣
really key to understanding neural
真正了解神经的关键
networks and finally this idea of
网络，最后这个想法
packages of help of using code that
使用代码的帮助包
other programmers have written and
其他程序员写的和
taking it to help ourselves and you know
拿它来帮助自己，你知道
hopefully down the line as we become
希望我们成为时候
better and better programmers we're able
我们能够做得越来越好的程序员
to make our own code our own packages
使我们自己的代码成为我们自己的包
that we can share with other programmers
我们可以与其他程序员分享
so I want you to take those three things
所以我希望你能把这三件事拿走
gradient descent loss functions and
梯度下降损失函数和
packages to help the world of
包帮助世界
programming get better and I want you to
编程变得更好，我要你
take those ideas and think about them
接受这些想法并思考它们
read more about them on your own time
在自己的时间阅读更多关于它们的信息
and yeah I hope you enjoyed this live
是的，我希望你喜欢这个生活
coding portion of the style transfer
风格转移的编码部分
presentation I am Louis Gomez thank you
演讲我是路易斯戈麦斯谢谢你
for your time and I'll see you guys
为你的时间，我会看到你们
later bye
后来再见